Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath living mana
church family. Uh I want to invite you.
I want to invite you to take this time
to share this link and invite everyone
that you can because I need people we
need people to hear this message today.
And this is going to be an in-house
message, you guys. Um we're gonna have
to we're going to talk about some
in-house things that I think are very
important for God's people, especially
in the time that we're living in.
Um the title of the message today is
this man eateth with sinners. This man
eateth with sinners. I want to invite
you to pray with me. Heavenly Father,
we're asking Lord today that in a
special way you would please speak to
your people. Lord, hide me behind your
cross.
Lord, infuse me with your spirit. And
Lord, may the words I speak
be uplifting and glorifying to you. We
pray in Jesus name. Amen.
So guys, um I want to address something
uh that occurred over the last over last
Sabbath
that has now um
kind of gone
very public, let me say, uh within our
church.
So, a few months back, um I was invited
to actually speak at a religious liberty
event for um the 7th Day Adventist
Church in H uh the Hansen 7th Day
Adventist Church in Brooklyn, New York.
And I was told that there were going to
be several politicians there and that
these politicians were supposed to only
speak on religious liberty. So, they
were being invited, but we weren't sure
if they weren't sure if they were going
to come. And uh to me I was like, "Hey,
listen. If I if I'm able to be there and
to preach
a message on religious liberty and the
separation of church and state in the
presence of um politicians and I was
told there were going to be politicians
from the left, politicians from the
right." Uh and um I was like, "Lord,
what an opportunity. What an
opportunity." I was told they were not
going to be politicking. And um and so
anyway, we accepted the invitation
and uh when we got to New York last
weekend uh Friday and we were uh
fellowshipping with uh some of the uh
with actually one of the one of the uh
organizers of the of the event and I
remember we were there eating lunch uh
Friday afternoon and he was on a phone
with several of the the politicians
um uh offices. is and they were like
taking notes like okay so remember no uh
political talk. Um and then I I even
heard him over say make sure that they
greet the speaker the pastor that's
going to be speaking and in my head I'm
I'm kind of like they don't even know me
like but hey it's a formality so let it
be. And so,
uh, I'm looking forward to, you know,
hopefully meeting all of these
politicians because, man, what an
opportunity.
What an opportunity
to be able to share with them, even if I
don't get to do it that there. I don't I
mean, I didn't know how long they were
going to be sticking around or what. I
had no clue, but even if I got to meet
some of them, that the Lord would would
would be able to plant seeds later down
the road. I thought, man, what a great
opportunity. So, Sabbath morning comes
around
and um the only one that actually came
early and actually walked into the back
room while my wife and I were there uh
into the pastor's office was um Zoron
Mamani.
Zoran Mani.
I I didn't know what the guy looked
like. I never heard his name before.
I didn't know he was running for mayor.
because I don't follow New York
politics.
Like I think I may asked my wife, "Who's
that again?" And she's like, "The guy
that's running for mayor." This is like,
you know, 20, 30 minutes before he comes
into the office.
The name I heard was Hakee Jeff that was
going to be there. And that was that was
the name that I knew. And I was like, I
wonder if I'm gonna get to meet him. So
when Zon comes in and you know just a
little little bit earlier,
my wife was like, "That's a guy that's
running for mayor for New York." And I'm
like, "Okay, so okay, this is a guy
running for mayor for New York. I didn't
know he was as well known as he was. I
didn't know that."
And so he comes in and we greet and uh
we greet each other. Um and he, you
know, he's very just, you know, warm
personality. Um, and
someone took a picture of us and our our
exchange was probably like maybe a
minute. So then we all have to go out
and it's only him. He's the only one
there. Some of the other politicians
don't come till later. And I remember as
I was sitting sitting down in the pew
and I was sitting next to one of the
organizers and he was just like he was
saying to me, "Lord, please do not do
not let them, you know, go off course.
We have done everything we could to let
them know please stay on religious
liberty."
And I said to him, "Yeah, you know how
those YouTube channels go. Uh they just
looking for something.
So Zoron gets up and he's speaking and
uh he he uh says I want to thank I don't
even know what he said. I think he said
I mess. What?
He butchered my name. And I was like
well no one's going to even recognize
that. And I just kind of chuckled in my
mind like yeah cuz he doesn't know me.
evil Eevee Eevee my whatever he said.
And so uh um you know they say what they
say and some of them you know veer off a
little bit and I'm just like but I know
that the that that the leaders
instructed them do not speak on anything
political. This is about religious
liberty. And they all agreed. So I get
up and I do my sermon. It's on
Revelation chapter 13. It's on the third
angel's message. It's on the close of
probation. It's on the the uh um uh uh
apostate Protestantism. It is our
message.
We leave the following day. And that
morning, my wife happened to post the
picture. I didn't even know she was
posting it. Posted the picture
um on her Instagram. I had no idea that
she that she had done that. And in the
picture, she tagged me, Ivormeyers. And
then she thought she was tagging uh uh
Zoron in a way that to say, "Hey, you
know, this is a way that, you know,
trying to stay connected with him so
that he could see, hey, we posted this,
you know, we posted the picture."
Um, and
the post that she chose when all the I
mean, the tag that she chose when all
the tags came up was uh Zoron for mayor.
So, it looked like she was endorsing
Zoron for mayor. And I didn't know this
till after the plane landed in
Huntsville, Alabama. And um somebody
calls me and says, "Pastor, uh there are
people saying that you endorsed uh the
guy running for mayor." And I was like,
"Why would I endorse somebody that I
don't know that I just met that I don't
know about his politics? Like I just met
him. That doesn't make sense." And they
were like, "Well, on your wife's
Instagram there's a picture." And I'm
like, "But that that's just a picture."
And they were like, "Well, it says Zoron
for mayor." And I was like, "What?"
So, I opened my phone, looked at the
picture, and I was like, "This
is saying that you're, you know, we're
endorsing
uh this guy for mayor." And she was
like, "No, I'm tagging him." And I was
like, "Well,
we got to tag him with something else
because we're not endorsing him." And
she was like, "Okay." And it looks like
this is his wrong tag anyway. So, she
took the picture down, put it back up.
By the way, they had already told me
this picture has already been shared and
people are saying you're endorsing a
candidate. If I had been endorsing a
candidate, the picture would still be up
with the hashtag.
So, all of this to say you guys that um
that later that even I actually put up a
post and said, "Hey guys, no, this is
not what happened." And that was it you
guys. and I became a Muslim
uh supporter.
What are you doing standing with this
man? He's a Democrat. He's evil. He's
wicked. And in essence,
the sentiment was this man taketh
pictures with sinners. There is a basis
of the message, you guys. There's a
basis of the message. I remember a few
uh within last month a lot of my
Adventist brothers and sisters were
talking about the importance of context
and how you can't take a sentence from
someone online out of context and you
know you got to look at the context and
and even though things you know may seem
X Y and Z you got to look at the context
and so surely I was like well you know
they're going to they're going to
consider context they're going to know
that but no no the the same people that
were talking about context context
suddenly didn't matter.
This is the foundation, guys. I'm I'm
setting the foundation, the stage
because videos were made and and none of
the people ever stopped to say, "Hey,
let's go
and talk to Pastor Myers and see, hey,
what was the situation behind this?"
Like, what happened? It's all right to
be confused and say, "Hey, that you know
what was going on?" But before we jump
to conclusions and start putting out
posts and videos and things of that
nature, I want to speak to something
that I believe is happening in our
church that
that has the devil smiling.
I want to go to the screen and I want to
read a statement from uh the spirit of
prophecy. And the sermon has now begun.
Ellen White says these words. He says,
"I saw
that the very spirit of perjury that
would turn truth into falsehood, good
into evil, and innocence into crime is
now active.
Satan exalts over the condition of God's
professed people.
While many are neglecting their own
souls, they eagerly watch for an
opportunity to criticize and condemn
others.
All have defects of character, and it is
not hard to find something that jealousy
can interpret to their injury. Now, say
these self-constituted judges, we have
the facts. We will fasten upon them an
accusation from which they cannot clear
themselves. We got the picture, y'all.
We have the picture and we have the
hashtag. It is the smoking gun.
They wait for a fitting opportunity and
then produce their bundle of gossip and
bring forth their tidbits.
Let me talk about this definition of
perjury for a moment because she says
here,"I saw the spirit of perjury." Let
me read it again. I saw that the very
spirit of perjury that would turn truth
into falsehood, good into evil, and
innocence into crime is now active and
so among God's people. So, what is
perjury?
Perjury is the offense of willfully
telling an untruth in a court after
having taken an oath or affirmation.
That's what perjury is. I want to read
on and I want you to notice this. Uh the
prefix purr in Latin often meant
harmful.
So witnesses who perger themselves do
harm to the truth by knowingly telling a
lie. Not all lying is perjury. Only
lying under an oath. So perjury perjury
generally takes place either in court or
before a legislative body such as
Congress. To avoid committing perjury, a
witness or defendant may simply take the
fifth, that is refuse to answer a
question because the answer might be an
admission of guilt. And the fifth
amendment to the constitution forbids
forcing a citizen to admit to being
guilty of a crime. Did you know
that for Christians,
taking the fifth when it comes to gossip
and spreading rumors is always the
safest thing to do. Why? Because Ellen
White just told us that the spirit of
perjury, she saw it running rampant in
the church. Now, you might say, "Well,
no, we're not in in a in a court of law.
But we're not in Congress. Uh uh we're
not before a legislative body. So and
and we're not take we haven't taken an
oath. But I want you to notice, beloved,
that Ellen White also says, "He who
accepts God as his sovereign must take
the oath of allegiance to him.
He must put on the Christian uniform and
bear a loft the banner that shows to
whose army he belongs. He must make an
open avow of his allegiance to Christ.
Concealment is impossible. Christ's
impress Christ impress must appear on
the life in sanctified works. In other
words,
when you and I became Christians, we
took an oath. You are under an oath. And
beloved, part of that oath is to reflect
and represent the character of Christ.
Part of that oath is found in Exodus
20:16, which says, "Thou shalt not bear
false witness against thy neighbor."
When you bear false witness against your
neighbor, when you have that spirit of
perjury,
you are breaking an oath. Y'all put a
one in the chat if you understand what
I'm saying.
As Christians, as Seventh Day
Adventists, we are under an oath
to tell the truth.
And when we willingly
either omit
the truth or twist the truth
to do harm to another person's
character,
you are breaking the oath. You are under
the spirit of perjury.
Listen to what she says. In their
efforts to carry a point, persons who
have naturally a strong imagination are
in danger of deceiving themselves and
deceiving others. They gather up
unguarded expressions from another, not
considering that words may be uttered
hastily and hence may not reflect the
real sentiments
of the speaker.
But those unpremeditated remarks, often
so trifling as to be unworthy of notice,
are viewed through Satan's magnifying
glass, pondered and repeated until
molehills
become mountains.
I am so glad that God has given us the
gift of the spirit of prophecy
to reveal the spirit of truth versus the
spirit of error.
There is something going on in our
church, beloved, that is very dangerous.
It is a spirit of perjury. It is a
spirit that says, "What dirt can I find
on the next individual to make myself
look good?
That is an antichrist
spirit. Let me keep reading. Is it
Christian charity to gather up every
floating report to unearth everything
that will cast suspicion on the
character of another and then take
delight in using it to injure him? Satan
exalts when he can defame or wound a
follower of Christ. He is the accuser of
the brethren. Shall Christians aid him
in his work? Let me keep reading. The
spirit of gossip and tailbearing is one
of Satan's special agencies to sow
discord and strife, to separate friends,
and to undermine the faith of many in
the truthfulness of our positions.
Brethren and sisters are too ready to
talk of the faults of and errors they
think exist in others and especially in
those whom have borne unflinchingly the
message of reproof and warning given
them of God.
The children of these complainers listen
to me. When children see this stuff
going on, y'all listen to what she says.
The children of these complainers listen
with open ears and receive the poison of
dissatisfaction.
Parents are thus blinded, caught closing
the avenues through which the hearts of
the children might be reached. How many
families season their daily meals with
doubt and questioning? They dissect the
characters of their friends and serve
them up as dainty desserts. A precious
bit of slander is passed around the
board to be commented upon not only by
adults but by children. In this, God is
dishonored. Jesus said, "In as much as
you have done it unto the least of
these, my brethren, you have done it
unto me." Matthew 25:40. Therefore,
Christ is slighted and abused by those
who slander his servants. And listen to
this next sentence. The names of God's
chosen servants have been handled with
disrespect and in some cases with
absolute contempt by persons whose duty
it is to hold them up. You know, I
remember in the Bible the story of David
and Saul. David and Saul. And and David
had such a respect for God's anointed
that even in that anointed man's
absolute corruptness,
David said, "Do not touch the Lord's
anointed."
David had that kind of reverence. And
I'll tell you
that kind of thing is gone in our
church. The the level of of respect due
to one another, it's not that the pastor
is higher than this person. The level of
respect due to one another is
disappearing
within our church.
It's happening.
So,
um um I'm going to address something
else very quickly and then I'm I'm this
is setting the foundation for what you
are about to see and you're all about to
understand something that that is
absolutely crucial you guys because one
of the complaints that I typically get
and I even got over this sermon was all
you do is talk about
Christian nationalism
and Revelation chapter 13 and you're not
talking about this and this and this and
this and therefore you are unbalanced.
Therefore, you are unbalanced, pastor.
You're biased.
You lean this way.
You're not fair.
You don't talk about X, Y, and Z, but
you're always talking about A, B, and C.
So guys, we're about to go through a
lesson that I hope you will never
forget. This is from the Bible. Please,
I need y'all to focus. Let's follow.
Let's let let's move along. Second Peter
chapter 1 verse 21. The Bible says, "For
the prophecy came not in old time by the
will of man, but holy men of God spake
as they were moved by the Holy Ghost."
So here's what I want you to understand
you guys. The Holy Ghost moved the men
of the Bible,
the prophets, the authors, the writers
to speak and write what they wrote.
meaning the entire Bible.
The entire Bible
was inspired by the Holy Spirit. Now,
why is that important? John 16:7 says
this, "Nevertheless, I tell you the
truth. It is expedient for you that I go
away. For if I go not away, the
comforter will not come unto you. But if
I depart, I will send him unto you. And
when he has come, he will reprove the
world of sin and of righteousness and of
judgment. In other words, the work of
the Holy Spirit was to reprove. That was
one of the jobs of the Holy Spirit, to
reprove, to rebuke. Therefore, it might
be a good idea for us to go back through
the Bible and see how
the Holy Spirit rebuked. In what way can
we find a pattern of rebuke
according to how the spirit did it? And
so here's what we're going to do. We're
going to go through the whole Bible and
we're going to we're going to trace this
pattern and you're going to see
something absolutely mindblowing unfold.
Now, how many of you want to be in
unison with the Holy Spirit? Just put a
one in the chat if you want to be in
unison with the Holy Spirit. Here's what
we're going to do you guys. We're going
to see can we find a pattern, a ratio
of the Holy Spirit. Let's let's see if
we were to trace the entire Old
Testament. And by the way, here's what I
did. I went to to chat GPT and I said,
"Chat, I have a question.
I want you to take all the warnings of
the Old Testament and tell me how many
of those warnings inspired by the Holy
Spirit, how many of those warnings were
directed to unbelievers
and how many of those warnings were
directed to God's own people? And here's
what Chat GPT said. Chad GBT put out a
number for me and said approximately 70
to 85%
of the Holy Spirit's focus on reproving
in the Old Testament was towards
those professing to believe in God.
Y'all put a one in the chat. Put a one
in the chat if you could see that
clearly.
Most of the books of the Old Testament
are directed at the people of God.
That would make sense.
The Old Testament was written for
the people of God.
All right. So, so what about the New
Testament? Interestingly enough, in the
New Testament, if we were just to look
at Jesus, the Holy Spirit working
through Jesus, I want you to note what
Matthew chapter 10:5 says. Then these 12
sent forth and commanded, then tw these
12 Jesus sent forth and commanded them,
saying, "Go not into the way of the
Gentiles, and into any city of the
Samaritans, and to you not. But go ye
rather to the lost sheep of the house of
Israel." Interestingly enough, Jesus
says, "I've only been sent unto the lost
sheep of the house of Israel."
So, I asked Chat GBT, "Hey, chat,
how much rebuking did Jesus do to
unbelievers
versus
to the people who claimed to serve God?"
Chat GBT's response. Roughly 80 to 90%
of Jesus's rebukes
were toward people professing to serve
God.
There is barely no rebuke
to a Roman, to the Roman soldiers,
to the unbelievers, to the ungodly. Now,
we might stop and ask a question. I
might stop and ask a question. Hey, hey,
would you all say that Jesus was being
balanced? Put a five in the chat if you
think Jesus was being balanced. Put a
eight in the chat if you think Jesus was
being unbalanced. Because Jesus, it
seems that you are not calling out the
sins of the Romans enough. You are only
focused, Jesus,
on what those who profess to serve God
are doing. Jesus, you're not being very
balanced.
Your preaching, Jesus, seems to only
focus on those who profess to serve God.
Why aren't you talking more about the
Romans?
unbeliever? I fear that some of us, the
way we have gotten in our thinking
today, would accuse Jesus of being
biased in his preaching.
All right, how about this? Let's go to
the epistles. And I'm going to show you
something, you guys. I want you to check
this out. I want to look at every
epistle. And we're going to run through
this very quickly. I just want to show
you how they all begin. So 1 Corinthians
chapter 1:2, to all that be in Rome, I'm
sorry, Romans chapter 1:7. To all that
be in Rome, beloved of God, called to be
saints. Wow. Did you know the book of
Romans was not written to unbelievers?
Did you know the book of Romans and
everything in it was directed to the
saints in Rome?
How about 1 Corinthians 1? 1 Corinthians
1:2. Unto the church of God which is at
Corenth. 2 Corinthians 1:2. Unto the
church of God which is at Corenth.
Galatians chapter 1:2. And all the
brethren which are with me unto the
churches of Galatia. Ephesians to the
saints which are at Eph Ephesus.
Philippians to all the saints in Christ
which are at Philippi. Colossians to the
saints and faithful brethren in Christ
which are at Coloss uh Colasse
Thessalonians unto the church of
Thessalonians Thessalonians unto the
church of Thessalonians that's first and
second Thessalonians Timothy Paul unto
Timothy my own son in the faith second
Timothy Paul to Timothy my beloved son
in the faith Titus to Titus my own son
after the common faith Fleiman Paul a
prisoner of Jesus Christ and Timothy our
brother unto Fleiman our dearly beloved
and fellow laborer and to our beloved
Beloved Aphia and Archipus our fellow
soldier and to the church in thy house.
Hebrews God who at sunundry times and in
diverse manner spake in time past unto
the fathers by the prophets has in these
last days spoken unto us by his son.
We're almost there you guys. James
chapter 1. James to the 12 tribes which
are scattered abroad. He first Peter
chapter 1 to the strangers scattered
through Pontius and Galatia, Capidosia,
Asia, Bithnneia elect according to the
fornowledge of God the father. Uh,
second Peter, Simon Peter, to them that
have obtained like precious faith. First
John, that which we have seen and held,
declare we unto you that we may have f
that you may have fellowship with us,
and truly our fellowship is with the
father and with the son Jesus Christ. 2
John 1, to the elder and the elect lady
and her children whom I love in the
truth. Third John, to the elder and to
unto the well-beloved Gaes. Jude, Jude
to them that are sanctified, revelation
to the seven churches which are in Asia.
Do y'all see what just happened? Every
epistle, you guys, these epistles,
listen carefully to me, they were not
written to unbelievers.
So all the council, all the rebuke in
these books
are towards
believers.
The entire Bible
written towards
believers, rebuke towards believers. And
in fact, the rebuke when when it dealt
with the the Gentiles or the Romans or
the unbeliever, the rebuke was don't be
like them.
So I asked chat GBT, what is the
percentage of internal rebuke versus
rebuke for the unbeliever? And again,
wow, look at that. 85 to 95% from Acts
all the way to Revelation is focused on
rebuke of professed believers. And I got
to ask you a question for those of you
who say, "Oh, you know, your preaching
is is unbalanced. You you only do this
percent of this, but you do a whole
bunch of that." Would you say that the
Bible and Jesus and the prophets were
unbalanced?
So,
let's just break down the book of
Revelation. I asked chat GPT the same
question and
it says 80 to 90%
of the book of revelation is focused
on the believers.
There is a chapter Revelation 11 that
speaks to atheism. Revelation chapter 9
and 10 or 8 and 9 that speaks to the
rise of Islam. But by far, the majority
of the book is exposing a counterfeit
Christian power.
Let's talk let's talk for a moment about
the spirit of prophecy.
So, we've looked at the Bible and we've
seen that there is this ratio that keeps
popping up 80 to 90%
Rebuke
is given to those who profess Christ and
very little to those to the unbelievers.
And so I said, hm, what about the
testimonies? By the way, this is so
interesting, you guys. So, so when I put
in the testimonies, here's what Chach
Chat GBT said. 70 to 85% is internal
rebuke. Now it's interesting that the
testimonies are called the testimonies
to the churches.
That's what it's called the testimony.
The testimonies to the churches. In
other words, the testimonies are not for
the unbeliever.
But you know what happens you guys? You
know what happens? What book? Let me ask
you, what book
would you give to an atheist that was
written by Ellen White? What book would
you give to an unbeliever?
Someone who is not a an a Christian
that believes in the Bible already, but
is doesn't believe in anything else,
doesn't believe in the B, doesn't know
Jesus. What book would you give of Ellen
White's?
Come on, y'all. Y'all y'all know, right?
Are y'all putting it in the chat?
You're either saying Desire of Ages or
Steps to Christ. Wow.
How much rebuke do you think is in steps
to Christ
for the unbeliever? The person that's
trying to make their way to Jesus, the
person that doesn't know Christ.
Isn't that interesting?
It seems like the writings of the spirit
of prophecy actually follow along the
same ratio of the Holy Spirit that we
see in the Bible. In fact, in fact, if
if we uh uh take the book the great
controversy and ask the same question,
how much of the book The Great
Controversy, which would be a book that
I would give, let's say, to someone who
believes in Jesus but has prophecy all
wrong.
That's the book that I would give to
them. I wouldn't give them steps to
Christ because they have already
accepted Christ. They they already said,
"Hey, I believe in Christ." So, I would
give I would give the person who claims
to believe in Jesus the great
controversy. How much rebuke do you
think is in the great controversy for
the unbeliever versus for a professed
Christian power? That's right you guys.
75 to 90%
of the book
and it says there is one chapter that
deals with the French Revolution.
There's one other chapter that deals
with Rome as it was persecuting the
early Christians.
BUT THE MAJORITY OF THE BOOK, and I
would ask a question, is Ellen White
being unbalanced in her approach?
Because now the big the the the the
battlecry seems to be the word balance.
Balance.
But beloved, we see what balance is in
the divine realm. We see what balance is
according to the Bible. The discip the
the Pharisees did not like Jesus because
they thought he was unbalanced.
They thought Jesus was unbalanced.
Y'all,
do you know what Ellen White says is the
cause of so much ungodliness in the
world? Let me read it to you. The light
esteemed the light esteem in which the
law of God is held even by religious
leaders has been productive of great
evil. The teaching which has become so
widespread that the device that the
divine statutes are no longer abiding
upon men is is the same as idolatry in
its effect upon the morals of the
people. Those who seek to lessen the
claims of God's holy law are striking
directly at the foundation of the
government of families and nations.
Religious parents fa failing to walk in
his statutes do not command their
households to keep the way of the Lord.
The law of God is not made the rule of
life. The children as they make homes of
their own feel under no obligation to
teach their children what they
themselves have never been taught. And
this is why there are so many godless
families. This is why depravity is so
deep and widespread. In other words, the
spirit of prophecy
which is the Holy Spirit
writing through write the Holy Spirit
moving Ellen White to speak says the
blame for the ungodliness of our society
lays at the feet of religious teachers
who claim that the law of God has been
done away with.
So then in our experiment we see after
when we recap we see wow look at that
there's this constant line of between 70
to 90% of the rebuke by the Holy Spirit
is always towards those professing to be
believers in God while only a small if
y'all ask me pastor why do you not focus
more on the ungodly unbelievers ers and
the people who are who are rejecting God
altogether. If you ask me why, beloved,
I will simply tell you I am following
the leadings of the Holy Spirit. That's
why I'm focusing on what Jesus f focused
on. I'm focusing on what Ellen White
focused on. I'm focusing on what the
entire Bible I'm following that pattern.
I'm following that ratio. That is what
balance is.
Balance is not what we think. Balance is
what God thinks.
Now the question you might ask is why
does the Holy Spirit follow this
pattern?
Why is the Holy Spirit pointing its
rebuke to those who profess to be
followers of God? And the answer is
found right here in Isaiah 60:1. The
Bible says, "Arise, shine, for thy light
is come and the glory of the Lord is
risen upon thee. For behold, the
darkness shall cover the earth, and
gross darkness the people, but the Lord
shall arise upon thee, and his glory
shall be seen upon thee, and the
Gentiles shall come to thy light, and
kings to the brightness of thy rising.
Lift up thine eyes round about sea. All
they gather themselves together. They
come to thee. Thy son shall come from
afar, and thy daughters shall be nursed
at thy side. Then thou shalt see and
flow together, and thine heart shall
fear and be enlarged, because the
abundance of the sea shall be converted
unto thee. The forces of the Gentiles
shall come unto thee. In other words,
beloved, what God is saying is that the
reason, listen to me y'all, the reason
why my emphasis is on those who profess
to know me is because they are the very
light I am trying to use to bring
non-believers and atheists and Gentiles
and Marxists and socialists and Muslims
and Buddhists and everybody else who
does not call the name of Jesus. I need
you believers to actually be light. And
when you are light, that's what's going
to draw them. But you are being
darkness. And darkness is is what is
securing them in what they believe.
Because when they look at you, all they
see is hate and animosity and darkness.
And y'all are not like us.
That's why God turns his rebuke
on the church.
And when I say the church, do not get
don't do not misstate what I'm saying.
When I say the church, I'm talking about
anyone anywhere in the world in any
denomination that claims to be a
follower of Jesus. Because the thing
that Jesus is most concerned about is
false representation. I have called you
to be a light in this world. And when
you begin to go out and tell people that
the Sabbath has been changed, that the
law of God has been done away with, that
when the dead die, they go straight to
heaven, you are not miss, you are not
representing the truth.
And so for those of us who know the
truth,
our major focus should be on any false
representation of what Jesus represents.
Our focus, beloved, is not on condemning
the gentile, the Muslim. Pastor, what
are you doing standing next to a Muslim?
How dare
you
disrespect
the character of Jesus by saying, "How
dare a believer be seen in the presence
of an unbeliever?"
That is straight up phariseism.
And in the name of God, I rebuke you,
whoever you are.
In the name of God, you will answer
to the Lord God Almighty
for having the same spirit of the
Pharisees who thought that they were too
good and holy to be found in the
presence of a gentile of an unbeliever.
Romans 2:22 says, "Thou says a man
should not commit adultery adultery.
Dust thou commit adultery? Thou that
aboreest idols, dust thou commit
sacrilege? Thou that makest thy boast of
the law, through breaking the law,
dishonest thou God? For the name of God
is blasphemed among the Gentiles through
you, as it is written.
Your
wicked
idea of what righteousness is
is what leads unbelievers to blaspheme
the God of heaven.
And everyone that possesses that spirit
ought to be rebuked
because that is not the spirit of our
savior. This man
eateth with sinners.
This man taketh a picture with sinners.
Explain yourself, pastor.
What meanth this picture?
The Bible says in 2 Timothy 3:16, "All
scripture is given by God by inspiration
of God, and is profitable for doctrine,
for reproof, for correction, for
instruction, and righteousness, that the
man of God, not the unbeliever,
the man of God may be perfect,
thoroughly furnished unto all good
works." So beloved, if the scripture is
for the man of God to be perfect, then
our role as believers is to help those
who are not men of God become men of God
so that the scripture that can then do
its work on him.
The Bible
is written
to the believer.
It is for the world.
But the instructions are for the
believer. And those instructions say you
are the light of the world. Now, now
that you got that right, now that you're
representing me right, go out and
witness. But what's happening is many of
us are taking a false witness of Jesus
to the world.
And we become so invol so caught up in
the false witness that it becomes easy
for us to false witness elsewhere.
There is a divinely inspired ratio. And
I'm not saying these numbers are set
solid. I'm simply saying God spent more,
the Holy Spirit spent more of its rebuke
on those professing to believe in God
than it did on the unbeliever.
But the Pharisees wanted to flip that
ratio. They didn't like that ratio. Why
you not talking about the Romans, Jesus?
Why are you always pointing out our
sins?
You must be done with the Romans.
You must be a secret Roman. You must be
down with the opposition. You must be
down with be elabub
because your messages, Jesus, are so
unbalanced.
You harp on us all the time. Yeah, I
used to listen to Jesus, but once I
really started listening to him, he's
just unbalanced, man. All he talks
about,
all he talks about, he never talks about
the Romans.
The Jews cultivated a spirit of
retaliation. In their hatred of the
Romans, they gave utterance to hard
denunciations and pleased the wicked one
by manifesting his attributes. Thus,
they were training themselves to do the
terrible deeds which he led them on. In
the religious life of the Pharisees,
there was nothing to recommend piety to
the Gentiles. Jesus bade them not to
deceive themselves with the thought that
they could in heart rise up against
their oppressors and cherish the longing
to avenge their wrongs. Pastor, what are
you doing with a Muslim?
That is the very spirit of Antichrist.
That is the very spirit of Satan.
That is a satanic
mentality.
Are you a Muslim now? Are you a
socialist? Or are you this? Are you
that?
Perjury. The spirit of perjury. And we
don't care. Do y'all do we understand
that for every false statement that you
make whether in secret or in public, do
you know do we not understand that you
are going to have to stand before God
and explain why you said this of
someone's character? Why you said that
that this person really deep down thinks
this or says that? And even though he
says, "No, I didn't know THE GUY
BEFORE." YOU'RE LIKE, "NO, HE'S LYING
and and I have evidence to prove it." Do
you realize you guys that the spirit of
perjury will get you lost?
Do we not believe in an investigative
judgment? Do we think that's a joke? Do
you So listen y'all. Perjury is willing
to lie under oath. Which means some of
us are so deceived by the devil that we
would be willing to risk our salvation
to accuse another brother or sister
and think that we can read their hearts.
Do we believe in in an investigative
judgment or not?
Because how can you be willing to risk
your salvation by trying to read
somebody else's mind and say, "Well,
this is what they really think and what
they really feel.
I got the dirt on them."
And even though they're saying, "Nah,
no, no." Listen y'all, if someone
accuses you of being an Adventist, I
defend that all day long. If someone
accuses me of of uh uh you know being
believing in in uh um uh the Sabbath,
I'll defend that all day. If you accuse
me of believing in Sunday worship, how
can I defend something that's not my
position? How can I do that?
And when we put things upon people,
you guys, it is a spirit of perjury.
And so many of us in the church don't
even realize
that we are working our way to
destruction,
thinking that we're doing something
righteous.
Let me show you. Come on. We're not
done. We got more to go. Oh, you guys.
You guys listen.
Were there commands and traditions to be
treated with indifference? In fact, let
me go back. Let me go back. Yeah, here
it is.
The least difference of opinion
expressed by Christ was an occasion for
the Jews to resist and denounce him.
Wow. Does that sound like present day
a lot of present day people within
Adventism, y'all?
The least difference of opinion
expressed by Christ was an occasion for
the Jews to resist and denounce him.
At times they charged him with working
miracles through Beelub, the prince of
devils. The least mention of Christ as a
light to the Gentiles roused to fury the
NATIONAL PREJUDICE. THAT GUY'S A MUSLIM.
I MEAN A GENTILE. DON'T you know Jesus?
Don't you know what he's really trying
to do? The worst passions of the heart
were stirred. For the Pharisees had
taught the Jewish people to despise and
hate the Muslims. I'm sorry, the
Gentiles,
the unbeliever, the atheist,
the person that rejects God, the person
that doesn't think God exists. They were
taught to hate them.
Were their commands and traditions to be
treated with indifference and worse
still to be brushed away as error? Was
this man the son of a carpenter to be
accepted as knowing more than the
priests and rulers? They would show him
that he could not take the people from
them. They determined to put him to
death. And you know what they started
doing? She says spies were constantly
upon his track seeking to catch him in
his words that they might find
accusation against him. I'm going to
tell y'all a personal experience.
I got I got caught among sinners once
and it changed so much in my ministry
because people were like, "We caught you
hanging out with sinners."
I remember when the when the Black Lives
Matter thing was happening and I was
saying to myself, you know what, man,
Black Lives Matter, I I they're trying
to do right, but they don't have the
answer. They as an organization, they're
not the answer. Like what they're doing
is not the answer. The answer is only in
the gospel. And you know what? What a
perfect opportunity for us to show that
listen, Black Lives Matter, uh um uh the
NAACP, like they don't I mean, they're
doing what they think is right, but they
don't have the real answer. We have the
answer. The answer to bringing unity
between black and white, to bringing
unity between all races, to let people
know one race, many colors, one race,
many colors. The answer is the gospel.
So, you know what we're going to do?
Here's what we're going to do.
We're going to hold a peaceful protest.
We're going to let people know, hey, we
know that there's an issue. We We get
it. We understand. We're with you. We
know there's an issue. But here's what
we're going to do. We're going to take
we're going to we're going to lead a
peaceful demonstration. Then we're going
to march these people back to our
church. And then I'm going to preach to
them the everlasting gospel. And we led
about 400
people back to the front of our church.
a peaceful march and then they sat and
listened to me preach the gospel and
because the churches were closed because
it was co people were like when your
church opens up I want to come
nah
that's when I crossed the line you guys
I was caught
with Gentiles
I became a black lives matter supporter,
which I never was. I became a Marxist,
which I'm not. I became all I became a
racist.
I became so many things. And as I read
this statement, spies were constantly
upon his track, seeking to catch him in
his words that they might find
accusation against him. I can kind of
relate with that.
How can we be treating one another in
the church like this? How can we be
actually in a m in a mindset of trying
to destroy those that we disagree with?
Floating rumors. Listen, floating rumors
are often the destroyers of unity among
brethren. There are some who watch with
open mind and ears to catch flying
scandal. They gather up little incidents
which may be trifling in themselves but
which are repeated and exaggerated until
a man is made an offender for a word.
Their model seems to be report and we
will report it. These tailbears, these
YouTube channels,
these Facebook posts
are doing the work are doing Satan's
work with surprising fidelity, little
knowing how offensive their course is to
God.
If they would spend half the energy and
zeal that is given to this unholy work
in examining their own hearts, they
would find so much to do to cleanse
their souls from impurity that they
would have no time or disposition to
criticize their brethren and they would
not fall under the power of this
temptation. The door of the mind should
be closed against they say or I have
heard. We should not, why should we not,
instead of allowing jealousy or evil
surmising to come into our hearts, go to
our brethren. I saw a sermon you
preached the other day, my brother, and
I want to come to you and speak to you
and ask you, do you really believe?
Is this what you were say? Because maybe
I don't know. And instead of me jumping
to conclusions and saying, look at what
pastor so and so preached. You know
what? Let me go. Yes, it's public, but
because that's my brother and I love
him, let me go to my brother in private.
But you know what? It is a spirit of
hatred. Y'all listen to me carefully. It
is the spirit because I guarantee you,
every person that does this, if it were
their own mother, brother, father,
whatever, their own family member, they
would go to them in private and be like,
"Hey, is this what you really believe?"
Well, man, maybe you should, you know,
because people are going to say blah
blah blah blah blah. It is the lack of
love.
Period.
It is the lack of love dwelling in the
human heart that allows people to do
what they do when they do this unholy
work.
Why should we not instead of allowing
evil, jealousy or evil surmising come
into our hearts, go to our brethren and
after frankly but kindly setting before
them the things which we have heard
detrimental to their character and
influence pray with them and for them.
Nah, nah nah, that's not good enough.
While we cannot fellowship with those
who are the bitterest enemies of Christ,
we should cultivate that spirit of
meekness and love that characterize our
master. a love that thinkketh no evil
and is not easily provoked.
So, so the Pharisees were unhappy with
Jesus. They didn't like the balance. So,
they wanted to try to find a way to
begin to accuse him. And here's what
they began doing. You guys, I want you
to notice on the screen Luke 7:38.
Listen to what the Bible says. So this
woman uh uh stood at his feet weeping
and began to wash his feet with her hair
with her with her tears and did wipe
them with her hair hairs of her head and
kissed her feet kissed his feet and
anointed them with the ointment and
anointed them with ointment. Now when
the Pharisees which had bidden him saw
it, he spake within himself, saying,
"This man, if he were a prophet, would
have known what manner of woman that is
touching him, for she is a sinner." You
get that? She's a sinner, not me. I'm
not a sinner. And Jesus, if you knew
better, you would not have been caught
having this woman in your presence.
That was a spirit of Satan. That was a
spirit of the Pharisees. In Luke 15:1,
then drew near unto him all the
publicans and sinners for to hear him.
And the Pharisees and scribes murmured,
saying, "This man receiveth sinners and
eateth with them."
That was their complaint.
Jesus, explain this picture.
Explain this image. No, no, no, no. You
owe us an explanation. Instead of
seeing, wow, Jesus is connecting with
them. What they chose to see was based
on the evil intents
in their own hearts.
Explain it.
Come on, I'm all ears. Why
are you
with these publicans and sinners?
Luke 5:30. But the scribes and Pharisees
murmured against his his disciples,
saying, "Why do you eat and drink with
publicans and sinners? Don't you know
who that guy is?" Listen y'all.
Eating with publicans and sinners is one
thing, but that's a Muslim.
The spirit of Satan is running rampant
in our church,
in the hearts of people within our
church. Why? Because people in our
church have learned to hate. And I
wonder where we got that from.
We must be watching that occur someplace
else.
Cuz this spirit of hatred within
Christians is it's it's unfathomable.
Where are we getting the spirit from?
And then we hide it under a disguise of
righteousness. We're just being
righteous protectors of the truth. No,
you're being satanic.
That's what that is. Where where are we
learning this from?
Are we are we looking at other churches
and picking up their spirit?
Because it sure seems beloved, like
that's what's happening. Proverbs 11:1
says, "A false balance is an abomination
unto the Lord." A false balance is an
abomination unto the Lord. And so when
the Lord says, "Hey guys, this is my
balance.
Here is where the the majority of my
rebuke is going. and my correction is
going. And then there is where a little
of it is going. Why? Because they don't
even know the truth. But I have called
you to be witnesses to them. That's why
I put my attention on you. That's why
I'm trying to train you to be like me.
That's why I'm trying to train you to
reflect my character so that they will
see your light and come into the truth
and become one of you. But what you're
doing is you are exhibiting darkness to
them.
And beloved, I want you to understand
that it is that mind that that deception
that we can think we're in darkness
while walking while while professing to
serve Christ. I need you to see this in
John 18:28. Then led they Jesus from
Caiaphas onto the hall of judgment. And
it was early and they themselves went
not into the judgment hall, lest they
should be defiled, but that they might
eat the Passover. Do you see this? while
claiming
to not want to be defiled by touching or
being in the presence of Gentiles, of
Muslims,
of unbelievers,
of atheists,
of the left,
of the ungodly, of the Marxist, of the
socialist,
not realizing that that very spirit was
defiling them already, but yet they had
to keep the Passover.
Or how about this one? John 19:31.
Therefore, the Jews, because it was a
preparation that the body should not
remain upon the cross on the Sabbath
day, for the Sabbath was a high day,
besought Pilate that uh that their legs
might be broken and that they might be
taken away. And then they GO BACK TO TRY
TO KEEP the Sabbath.
We're observing the ritual, not
realizing that your heart is defiled.
When Mary takes the ointment and and and
and anoints Jesus's feet, you know what
Judas said? Here's what he said. John
12:5.
What? Listen. John 12:4. Then saith one
of his disciples, Judas's Scariot,
Simon's son, which should betray him.
Why was not this ointment sold for 300 p
and given to the poor? This he said, not
that he cared for the poor.
Not that you actually cared.
It's a Sabbath.
Religious liberty.
Religious liberty. That's an issue
worthy of Sabbath of of of of discussion
on Sabbath.
Ellen White talked about the the the
women's uh uh temperance movement and
inviting them to our CAT meetings
because it will be good to to make
connections with them.
And yet we we we we
how dare how
when that's not really the issue. the
real issue. Could it be possible that
the real issue is is if that picture was
with was with someone else
that it would not have been a problem?
Maybe someone of a different party. I
had people say, "Why did you take a
picture with someone of a different
party?" I couldn't because they didn't
come. They were invited. I would have
loved to
Would
you take a picture with a Ku Klux Clan
guy? Yep.
Yes, sir.
If I can make a connection with a Clue
Ku Klux Clan guy and win him to the
truth, you better believe it.
You better believe it,
beloved. We don't seem to understand. So
many of us don't seem to understand how
much our crying out against politics is
so hypocritical because we're actually
guided by politics
while claiming, "Oh, I'm not political,
but why do you need to take a picture
with this person and only that person?"
Really? Really?
Are we Are we being serious right now?
God wants people on the left saved and
he wants people on the right saved. And
he has a pattern. God wants God wants
Christians who are not of our faith
saved and he wants unbelievers who are
not of our faith saved. But he says to
the church, listen, I have called you to
preach a special message to Babylon.
Babylon is not the unbeliever, you guys.
Babylon is the fallen churches. Why?
Because the unbelievers are looking at
the big at the largest group of
professed followers of Jesus and seeing
nothing but hypocrisy.
And so we're trying to say, "Listen,
y'all bigger body of believers. What
you're doing is pushing them away. Here
is the actual truth. That's why God
wants us to focus over here."
But no, what we're doing IS WE'RE
ADOPTING THE HATRED of that bigger group
of Christians and we're going, "Yeah,
those evil unbelievers. Literally not
even thinking how Satan is just
destroying the work that God has called
us to do." We're not thinking.
We're not thinking.
Ellen White says, "The greatest
deception of the human mind in Christ's
day was that a mere ascent to the truth
constitutes righteousness." In all human
experience, a theoretical knowledge of
the truth has been proved to be
insufficient for the saving of the soul.
It does not bring forth the fruits of
righteousness. A jealous regard for what
is termed theological truth is often or
often accompanies a hatred of genuine
truth as is made manifest in the life.
What does she mean? Here's what she
says. The darkest chapters of history
are burdened with the record of crimes
committed by bigoted religionists. The
Pharisees claimed to be the children of
Abraham and boasted of their possession
of the oracles of God. Yet these
advantages did not preserve them from
selfishness, maligny, greed for gain,
and the basis hypocrisy. They thought
themselves the greatest religionist of
the world, but their so-called orthodoxy
led them to crucify the Lord of glory.
The same dangers still exist today. Many
take it for granted that they are
Christians simply because they
subscribed to certain theological
tenants, but they have not brought the
truth into practical life. They have not
believed it and loved it and therefore
have not receive the power and grace
that comes through sanctification of the
truth. Men may profess faith in the
truth, but if it does not make them
sincere, kind, patient, forbearing,
heavenly minded, it is a curse to its
possessor. And through their influence,
it is a curse to the world.
Beloved, I need you to understand
that I'm speaking with passion because
what is happening in our church, when
you make a man an offender because of a
word, when you make a man an offender
because of a picture, and you start to
fill in the blanks and Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Really, I was checking it out and and
him and this guy go way back. They
actually really know each other. and we
start going down the rabbit hole of the
conspiracies. I'm telling you beloved,
Satan is planting a spirit within the
members of our church. And if we do not
wake up from it, you are running the
risk of eternal loss.
The spell
that so many of us are under must be
broken.
This man ate with sinners and we now
have the goods on him.
Reviewing Herald June 2, 1896. Jesus was
accused of eating with publicans and
sinners at as though it were a crime to
associate with the fallen. WHAT ARE YOU
DOING with him? Jesus, explain.
By this accusation, they insinuated that
Christ liked to associate with the
sinful and vile. He likes this. Deep
down inside, this is who Jesus is. And
he doesn't even realize their wickedness
and he was insensible to their
wickedness. That's what she says. They
really he really like he likes the
publicans. This is evidence that he's
unbalanced. He's rebuking us all the
time. He's rebuking the church all the
time. But he's not saying nothing to the
sinners. If he were a true prophet, they
said he would harmonize with them. Do
what we want you to do. Preach what we
want you to preach. Pastor, why aren't
you preaching what I want you to preach?
If he were a true prophet, if he were a
true believer, if he was actually
present truth, he would harmonize
with them and he would treat the
publicans and sinners and Muslims and
atheists and leftists and socialists and
Marxists with the indifference they
deserved. It angered these guardians. I
never seen so many angry people in my
life like I have in the last week.
Wow.
It angered these guardians of society
that he with whom they were continually
in controversy, yet whose purity of life
a condemned them should meet in such
apparent sympathy with social outcasts.
How dare you meet with a social outcast.
No Adventist should be seen
with a social outcast.
They classed him with sinners because he
associated with sinners. But Jesus did
not seem at all abashed by the charge.
He looked keenly at his accusers and
said, "I came not to call the
self-righteous but sinners to
repentance."
They passed by the very ones who needed
help, who would receive the light that
they rejected, who were near the kingdom
of heaven, nearer the kingdom of heaven
than those who looked upon them as
sinners, whose society would contaminate
their morals.
You guys, Ellen White is a prophet,
y'all. She is a prophet.
She says, "Yet we should not exclude
ourselves from the world, for our
Christian experience is to be the light
of the world." This exactly what I've
been trying to say, you guys. We should
not exclude ourselves from the world,
for our Christian experience is to be
the light of the world.
The society of unbelievers will do us no
harm if we mingle with them for the
purpose of connecting them with God and
are strong enough to spiritually
withstand their influence.
It was taught by the Jews that before
God's love is extended to the sinner, he
must first repent. He must first cease
to be a Muslim. He must first cease to
be a leftist. He must first cease to be
a socialist. He must first cease to be a
Marxist.
In their view, repentance is a work by
men which earned the favor of heaven.
And it was this thought that led the
Pharisees to exclaim in astonishment and
anger, "This man receiveth sinners."
According to their ideas, he should
permit none to approach him. Why'd you
take a picture?
He should permit none to approach him
but those who had repented.
This is why Jesus says, "Beloved, many
will say in that day, Lord, Lord, have
we not in thy name cast out devils and
in thy name done many wonderful works?
Then I'll profess to them, depart from
me. I never knew you." I need you to
understand that people who claim the
name of Jesus and yet do not have the
character of Jesus will be rebuked by
Jesus when Jesus comes again.
All right.
So guys, now now I'm about to show you
something and please lock in.
We can now see why the books of Daniel
and Revelation focus not on the atheist,
not on the socialists, not on Marxism,
not on communism. It focused on a
counterfeit Christianity. And you'll
remember in Daniel 7:25 that this little
horn power, the Bible says, would speak
great words against the most high and
would think to wear out the saints and
think to change times and laws. And many
of us understand
that what this little horn power was
doing in changing times came up with two
new schools of thought. Futurism saying,
"No, it's not us. The enemy is in the
future." Predtoism, no, it's not us. The
enemy is in the past. The thing they
were doing was they realized that 80% of
the warnings of the books of Daniel and
Revelation were pointing to them. And so
they were trying to move the finger from
them and say, "NO, GUYS, LOOK, THE enemy
is over there. The enemy is in the
past."
In the very same way,
in the very same way, could it be
possible
that the second power that comes up out
of the earth that is that claims to be a
Christian power,
could it be possible
that the devil is working through that
power to create enemies that aren't
really the enemies?
They are not the main enemies.
Beloved, I need you to understand that
that that what Christian nationalism,
what modern Christian, what apostate
Protestantism is doing right now is
they're saying, "Listen guys, the enemy
is atheism and socialism and Marxism and
Muslims. And those are the people we
need to be aware of." Why? because a
devil doesn't want the world to realize
that the real adversary is actually
working under the disguise of
Christianity. But God knew that. And so
he raised up a movement to say, "Guys,
stay focused.
I need you to call out Babylon because
nobody else is going to do it." the rest
of the Christian world, they're calling
out socialism and they're pretending
that these are the enemies when you know
that the actual enemy coming at the end
of time will be under the guise of
Christianity. So, so my Adventist
church, I need you to lock in and stay
focused. But you know what? Many of us
have been drinking the wine of Babylon
and are now demanding that God's 8010
scale become 5050 or better yet 9010.
That's what's happening. So now you
don't speak about about atheism enough
and you don't speak about homosexuality
enough and you don't speak you don't
condemn the homosexuals enough and you
don't condemn the atheists enough and
you're unbalanced because you're not
doing what the other churches out there
in the world are doing. YOU'RE WHY ARE
YOU SO focused
on apostate Protestantism? Why are you
so focused on this second beast? Leave
the beast alone. Why don't you go deal
with with a that's balance. No, beloved,
that's apostasy.
That's moving away from the working of
the spirit, the spirit of God. It's it's
ratio in the Old Testament, in the in
the Gospels, in the New Testament, in
the great controversy, in the writings
of the spirit of prophecy. They It's
It's the same thing all across.
And now we want to change the ratio.
Now, we want to get mad
when our message is preached. How are
you gonna get mad about somebody
preaching Revelation chapter 13? Because
you're like, "Well, you're not being
balanced." No. No.
When you drink the wine of Babylon, you
no longer know what balance is. You are
off balance.
You are drunk with the wrath of Babylon.
And the wrath of Babylon is a wrath
directed at the Muslim. It's a wrath
directed at the atheist. And now you've
adopted that wrath. That's a Muslim.
What are you doing with them? That's an
atheist. Oh, that's the left. What are
you doing with them? CC. You would take
a picture with a left, but you wouldn't
take a picture with the right.
Stupidity. Foolish arguments. not
realizing that both souls need to be
saved.
You're you're willing to extend context
to individuals who it may easily be
said, "Oh, they're racist." No, no, no,
NO, NO, NO, NO. IT'S THE CONTEXT,
CONTEXT, CONTEXT. But all you need is
one one thing
for a fellow believer in the Lord, for a
fellow believer in the faith and be
like, "See what we've been telling you.
I told you. I told you. It was just a
matter of time. I I told you."
But let me tell you something, you guys.
Satan will never trip up the work of
God.
He may trip us up. He may trip me up. He
may lead us to make decisions that we're
not the best. He But he'll never trip up
the work of God.
We can say amen and hallelujah to that.
My thing is let us not help Satan in his
work.
Let us not help Satan in his work.
Because who but Satan would want to
destroy the character and the reputation
of fellow believers in the church.
You help me understand that
that is the work of the enemy. That is
the work of the devil.
We're getting ready to close you guys. I
need y'all to understand this.
Uh there have been apparitions of Mary
and in these apparitions of Mary, I'm
not going to go into in fact let me let
me just I'm going to pull one up here.
This is from the Fatim one of the Fatima
visions and I'm going to put it up on
the screen. You'll see it here. In an
interview in 1946, Fatima Seir Lucia dos
Santos said, "What our lady wants is
that the pope and all the bishops of the
world consecrate Russia to her
immaculate heart on one special day. If
this is done, she will convert Russia
and there will be peace. If it is not
done, the errors of Russia will spread
through every country in the world."
Asked whether this meant that the entire
world could be overrun by communism,
Lucia said yes. Lucia was also asked
about whether the United States would
also fail into fall into communist
hands. And again, her reply was yes.
Listen to me, y'all. There are
administers who are taking this this
prophecy from Mary seriously,
who really believe that communism
is an endtime player and could very well
take over America if we And you guys,
it's it's absolutely mind-blowing
that for people who have been given the
spirit of prophecy
that she says almost nothing
about communism or Mark. If she's a
prophet,
we would expect her to be able to warn
us along with Daniel and along with
Revelation of what comes at the end of
time. But here we are embibing in
Babylonian wine and now actually talking
about, hey, our greatest threat is
communism and Marxism and pastor, why
are you always talking about apostate
Protestantism?
In fact, pastor, you're in apostasy
because all you talk about is prophecy.
Is it It's stunning
that my whole ministry is based on
warning against the separate separation
of church and state.
Now, there's some articles out there
that are like, "Pastor blurs the line of
separation of church and state." No, no
context. Just hey, context doesn't
matter right now. What matters right now
is
we want to do the work of the enemy. And
that's the most important thing.
That that's that's a very dangerous
spirit, you guys. And it is a spirit
that is running rampant in our church.
It is a spirit that is being directed.
Listen, I know that you listen listen
y'all.
Somebody needs to say something.
This spirit needs to stop. This spirit
of blood searching of of of of looking
for blood because that's what it is.
We're looking for when ah we got the
dirt. Ah, look what we're making people
offenders for a word. And the spirit of
cannibalism needs to stop you guys.
Ellen White said this. As the storm
approaches, a large class who have
professed faith in the third angel's
message, but have not been sanctified
through obedience to the truth, abandon
their position, and join the ranks of
the opposition. By uniting with the
world and partaking of its spirit, they
have come to view matters in nearly the
same light. And when the test is
brought, they are prepared to choose the
easy popular side. I need you to
understand what the easy popular side
is. The easy popular side will be
apostate Protestantism. That is the side
she is saying that many Adventists will
join with. Why? Because they so
connected themselves with their same
spirit with the spirit of wrath and the
spirit of anger and the spirit of hatred
towards the non-believer and the Muslim
and the homosexual and the atheist that
they lost the character of Christ and
now they have become so united. Listen,
right now you have Adventists protecting
and defending apostate Protestantism,
saying, "Stop preaching about that.
Focus on the things that really matter.
You're not being balanced."
Revelation 18:2, this is our closing
verse. This is our next closing verse.
Revelation 18:2, the Bible says about
this Babylon, this Babylon the great is
fallen has fallen and has become the
habitation of devils and a hold of every
foul spirit and a cage of every unclean
and hateful bird. I need you to
understand beloved that Babylon is
filled with a hateful spirit and many of
us have adopted that hateful spirit. It
is seen. It is publicly seen.
People are spotting it.
It is publicly being manifested
and towards God's church and towards
God's people.
We have been called with a message to
give a message that says, "Come out of
Babylon, my people." That's the message.
That is the message.
If Jesus said this, "You are the light
of the world. A city set on a hill
cannot be hid." If Jesus says, "We're
the light of the world, and everyone who
professes Christ is supposed to be the
light of the world." Then would it not
make sense that when the light of the
world gets it together, the Gentiles are
going to come? Would it not make sense?
Isn't that what God said? Isn't that why
God focuses so much on Babylon? Come out
of her, my people, and get into the real
light so that the loud cry and the
Gentiles can be converted unto truth.
Isn't that what it's all about?
Beloved, I'm making a special appeal.
And that appeal is this.
We need to put down the cup of wrath.
We need to put down the cup of of of of
wickedness. We need to put down
the spirit of perjury.
We need to focus
on cleansing our own characters.
We need to focus on preaching the
unadulterated
truth.
We need to stop with this false balance.
Well, you talked 50% about this. Why
don't you talk 50% about that? Jesus
didn't do that. The disciples didn't do
that. Ellen White didn't do that. Stop
with the false balances and begin to
follow the leading of the spirit.
The ratio is there for us.
Put down the cup.
Turn your weapons away from one another
and let us focus on the mission that God
has called us to do.
It is interesting
that a lot of the these things Oh,
pastor Myers, he was standing with this
guy. Never never said go check out the
sermon.
never said, "Go listen to the sermon
that he preached."
A and and and and those who do who one
individual actually said in his sermon,
he did not talk about the sins of
ungodly people and therefore the sermon
is apostasy.
You guys, we are we are drifting
very far away from the ideal that God
has for his church.
It is time to put down the cup.
It is time
to stop doing the work of the accuser of
the brethren. And it is time for us to
be about our father's business
to win souls
to speak truth and to be the light that
Jesus has called us to be.
That is my prayer.
And I'm going to put that I'm going to
ask you to put a one in the chat.
Pastor, that's me.
I've been drinking that cup.
I've had the spirit of anger. I've had
the spirit of of wrath. And I don't know
where it came from.
And along with that spirit of wrath
comes a spirit of accusation. It was in
the Pharisees and it's in many of God's
people now. And and we're making stuff
up in our minds and filling in blanks to
things that are not reality. and the
devil. This is the way the devil is
going to lead so many who claim to
believe in present truth to ultimately
join with the enemy at the end of time.
We ought to be praying for one another
and not praying on one another.
Heavenly Father,
Lord, forgive us as a people
for seeking
to catch a brother or a sister
for seeking to to to do harm, perjury.
Whether that is because it brings views
or whether it is because it makes people
feel like they are standing up for
present truth. Lord, rebuke that spirit.
Lord, what the enemy has taken for evil,
Lord, please turn that to good.
Lord, may may this instance be a lesson
to teach us how to plead the fifth
when it comes to our brothers and
sisters.
Teach us, Lord, to be willing to give
the benefit of the doubt to go talk to
the individual, Lord. But but but Lord,
please put that spirit of love within us
because that can only come from from the
spirit of love and so many of us are
lacking that love
as a result of it. Lord, this claiming
the truth becomes a curse to those who
don't have the spirit of love and it is
a curse to the world through their
influence. Lord, please forgive your
people.
Thank you Lord for hearing this prayer
and Lord may we be about your business
is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen and
amen.
May God bless you as you continue to
draw closer to the Lord. May he bless
you and keep you.
We will put the link uh to the afterglow
uh in the chat and uh we want to
encourage uh our members and anyone who
would like to to come and join us as we
fellowship. We'll talk about the Sabbath
school. We'll talk about the divine
service. Again, may God bless you and
keep you. Amen.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]